Value can also help you provide focus and again in something like this that's set up as, you know, we can accept it as a realistic, basic setting.
We understand that this is an indoor room because we have this back here and we can see a landscape out the back.
So, that's very handy and it gives us a sense of indoor and outdoor space.
What that also does though, is that look, the light of the sky is, that's the lightest thing in the room, just about.
In this whole picture, this is very white and look, it is surrounding the head of Jesus, the hero of the story.
So, the value is the fact that this is dark, this is light, and then Jesus has dark hair, creates the value contrast, that's going to create the most focus that's literally going to draw your eye there, because your eye always sees the focus first.
Even again, if you're not aware of it, your eye is doing its work and what the eye does first, it goes for the place of most contrast.
And, what did he do? He made sure that the place of most contrast was around Jesus. He also managed to do this, to some degree with color, and again, this is much harder to tell because Leonardo used paint experimental way of putting paint on as a fresco technique, that did not work and started falling off as soon as he finished it.
So, we can't know what this really looked like.
But, you can see that he used a limited pallet of colors, we've got red and blue for sure.
We've got some sort of green, blue over here.
And, there's a little bit of yellow, and the rest of it is sort of neutral.
But, again the most, the strongest contrasting color is, again on the central figure where Jesus is and not only that, but there's a diagonal there which also kind of strengthens that.
So, again we are, that idea that he's important is reinforced, even if we're not really aware that, that is, that we're being controlled that way.